4/19/25, 10:19 PM Richard Hendriks

Richard Hendriks

richard.hendriks@mail.com http://richardhendricks.example.com San Francisco, California

SUMMARY

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinal!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

SKILLS AND TECH

- Web Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript.
- Compression: Mpeg, MP4, GIF.

EXPERIENCE

Pied Piper CEO/President Dec 2013 — Dec 2014

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

VOLUNTEERING

CoderDojo Teacher Jan 2012 — Jan 2013

Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

PROJECTS

• **Miss Direction:** Won award at AIHacks 2016. Built by all women team of newbie programmers. Using modern technologies such as GoogleMaps, Chrome Extension and Javascript.

EDUCATION

University of Oklahoma Jun 2011 — Jan 2014

Bachelor - Information Technology, GPA: 4.0

PUBLICATIONS

Video compression for 3d media Oct 2014

AWARDS

Digital Compression Pioneer Award, Techcrunch

Nov 2014

INTERESTS

• Wildlife: Ferrets, Unicorns